<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on azazo&#39;s dump</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on azazo&#39;s dump</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:10:12 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Learn LLL! Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lattice-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:10:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lattice-1/</guid>
      <description>introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to write this for a LONG time (since about mid-2023 maybe), but I never got around to doing it. Somehow I&amp;rsquo;ve been super productive for the past few days though1, so I thought I might as well cross one more thing off of my to-do list.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m splitting this introduction into the two parts: the first part (which you are reading now) will cover the mathematical background on lattices, while the second part will cover the applications of lattices in cryptography CTF challenges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BlahajCTF 2025 Author Writeups &amp; Commentary</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/blahaj25-commentary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/blahaj25-commentary/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This year was the 3rd iteration of BlahajCTF, organised by a bunch of friends and I. We scaled up our event quite considerably as compared to last year, with about twice the amount people attending the physical finale/final round of the CTF. It certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely smooth sailing, but I really enjoyed working with the rest of the organisers and I&amp;rsquo;m glad that I had this chance to work with such talented and wonderful people.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sieberrsec Quals &amp; Finals 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sieberr25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 18:42:27 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sieberr25/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I participated in SieberrSec as part of the team ist es over für mich (the German team), with two other friends (here are writeups from my BGFC (Beautiful Genius Friend Cane)). It was my first time doing a CTF with them, and we managed to clinch first place for both qualifiers and finals, which I&amp;rsquo;m pretty proud of. I will be writing about some of the challenges that I managed to solve during and after the CTF.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICO and GreyCTF Finals 2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ico-grey25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 11:10:27 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ico-grey25/</guid>
      <description>introduction Over the last week of June, I participated in both the inaugural International Cybersecurity Olympiad and GreyCTF Finals. It was quite a fun experience (I spent an entire week at NUS), and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share my experience, along with some writeups for the more interesting challenges.&#xA;ICO The International Cybersecurity Olympiad was a seven1 day event, hosted by the NUS School of Computing. While the event wasn&amp;rsquo;t perfect2 I still rather enjoyed it overall.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating sums with the residue theorem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/residue-theorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 11:41:30 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/residue-theorem/</guid>
      <description>The residue theorem (or Cauchy&amp;rsquo;s residue theorem) is an incredibly powerful tool that can aid in evaluating integrals of analytic functions over closed curves.&#xA;Theorem: Let \(f(z)\) be a meromorphic function; that is, \(f\) is analytic except at a finite list of singularities, then \[ \oint_{C} f(z) dz = 2\pi i\sum \text{Res}(f, a) \] where \(\text{Res}(f, a)\) represents the residue of \(f\) at \(a\), and \(a\) runs over every singularity contained within the curve \(C\) in the sum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glasser&#39;s master theorem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/glassers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 18:06:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/glassers/</guid>
      <description>I haven&amp;rsquo;t posted in quite a while, and I feel pretty bad for not finishing the lattice posts yet (I&amp;rsquo;m working on them I promise) so here&amp;rsquo;s a short filler post about Glasser&amp;rsquo;s master theorem. I find it quite interesting, and the Wikipedia page doesn&amp;rsquo;t really contain much, so hopefully this will be useful.&#xA;the theorem For \(a, a_1, a_2, \dots, a_n, b_1, b_2, \dots, b_n \in \mathbb{R}\) and \(a_1, a_2, \dots, a_n &gt; 0\), we have that \[ \int_{-\infty}^\infty f\left(x+a-\sum_{i=1}^{n}\frac{a_i}{x-b_i}\right) dx = \int_{-\infty}^\infty f\left(x\right) dx \] Now let&amp;rsquo;s see an example of an integral that can be easily solved with this theorem.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IrisCTF 2025 writeups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/irisctf25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 18:06:12 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/irisctf25/</guid>
      <description>I played in IrisCTF 2025 as part of Untitled CTF Game, and got 34th place in the end. We were ahead of NUS Greycats at one point though :)&#xA;I liked the challenges from this CTF, and managed to solve three crypto, one misc, one rev and one pwn challenge in the end. However, I&amp;rsquo;ll only be writing about the three challenges that did not get point decayed to 50 points.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Don&#39;t Like The NUS NextBus App So I Did Something About It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nextbus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nextbus/</guid>
      <description>introduction NUS is a big1 university. Fortunately, there is an internal shuttle bus service that ferries students2 to and fro differnet locations, along with a handy app (the titular NUS NextBus) that displays bus routes and arrival timings.&#xA;Unfortunately, this app doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be very good.3&#xA;Recently, after being fed up with Google Maps not being able to display bus routes, I found a pretty cool website that not only shows all public bus stops and routes in Singapore, but also has a nice UI.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 14:26:25 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Well, after more than a year of strangling with Hugo, I proudly present to you: azazo&amp;rsquo;s blog!&#xA;Some things I&amp;rsquo;m planning to put here:&#xA;CTF writeups Stuff I find out after fucking around Maybe something about linguistics? We&amp;rsquo;ll see Stay tuned :3</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
